Guide to the Elemer Nagy collection ARCH125
University of Hartford Archives & Special Collections
- Publicity and Scrapbooks, 1932-2002; 1932-1971; undated; V
  - Newspaper Articles, 1942-1950 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 18)
  - Opera at Hartt-A new venture with Schorr, Nagy, 1942 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 3, Folder 1)
  - Marriage by Lantern Light/Old Maid and the Thief, 1943 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Models-Exhibition (Broadside), 1943 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 21)
  - Nagy and Fuller Brush Co., 1943 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 22)
  - Opera in the Music School-TV, 1943 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 23)
  - St. Joseph College-Ten Maidens, 1943 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 24)
  - Television-Hansel and Gretel, 1943 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 25)
  - Wadsworth Atheneum Lecture, 1943 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 26)
  - American British Art Center, 1943 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 27)
  - Hansel and Gretel, 1943 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 28-29)
  - Elmer Nagy-Model Set Designer, 1943 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 3, Folder 2)
  - Bastien and Bastienne/Frantic Physician/Herbert Graf, 1944 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 30)
  - Hansel and Gretel (Broadside), 1944 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 31)
  - Marriage by Lantern Light Newspaper Article, 1944 Apr 4 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 32)
  - Television-S. Langton Article, 1944 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 33)
  - Television-Marriage by Lantern Light, 1944 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 3, Folder 3)
  - St. Joseph College-Headless Horseman, 1944 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 34)
  - Opera-JHMF, 1944 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 35)
  - "Hartford Gives Nation Another First", 1945 Feb 25 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 6, Folder 1)
  - Nagy Speaker-NAO-Hartt Opera Guild, 1945 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 36)
  - Sister Angelica, 1945 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 37)
  - Emily Stephenson in Secret of Suzanne, 1945 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 38)
  - Marriage of the Devil/Secret of Suzanne/Arthur Neuman, 1945 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 39)
  - Marriage of the Devil/Secret of Suzanne-"Playing from Memory", 1945 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 3, Folder 4)
  - Marriage of the Devil/Secret of Suzanne-Expansion-Hartt Opera, 1945 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 3, Folder 5)
  - Beauty and the Beast/Amelia Goes to the Ball-Columbia U.-Nagy w/ Opera, 1946 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 40)
  - Central City Scrapbook, 1946-1950 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 7, Folder 3)
  - Barber of Seville-New York City Center, 1947 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 3, Folder 6)
  - Barber of Seville Newspaper Clippings, 1947 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 41)
  - Barber of Seville-Hartt Opera Guild, 1947-1948 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 42)
  - General Publicity, 1948 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 43, Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 3, Folder 8)
  - The Princess and the Vagabond-Freed, 1948 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 44)
  - New England Music Critics...Princess and the Vagabond (Freed), 1948 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 3, Folder 7)
  - General Publicity, 1949 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 45)
  - Albert Herring-Berkshire Music Center-Dido-St. Joseph-EMEC, 1949 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 46)
  - Central City, 1949 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 3, Folder 9)
  - General Publicity, 1950 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 3, Folder 10)
  - Die Fledermaus scenery and costumes by Elemer Nagy, 5 Dec 1951 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 47)
  - Central City, 1951 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 48)
  - General Publicity, 1951 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 3, Folder 11, Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 6, Folder 2)
  - General Publicity, 1952 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 3, Folder 12)
  - Merry Wives of Windsor [Central City], 1953 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 3, Folder 13)
  - General Publicity, 1953 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 3, Folder 14-15, Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 6, Folder 3)
  - Newsclips, 1953-1966 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 1, Folder 49)
  - Albert Herring-Central City, 1954 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 2, Folder 1)
  - Mary Washington College of the University of Virginia, 1954 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 2, Folder 2)
  - General Publicity, 1954 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 4, Folder 1, Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 6, Folder 4)
  - General Publicity, 1955 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 4, Folder 2, Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 6, Folder 5)
  - General Publicity, 1956 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 4, Folder 3-4, Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 6, Folder 6)
  - General Publicity, 1957 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 2, Folder 3, Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 6, Folder 7)
  - General Publicity, 1958 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 4, Folder 5)
  - General Publicity, 1959 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 4, Folder 6, Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 6, Folder 8)
  - General Publicity, 1960 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 5, Folder 1)
  - Hartt Opera Portfolio, undated [circa 1960] (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 7, Folder 4)
  - Don Pasquale, 1961 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 2, Folder 4)
  - General Publicity, 1961 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 5, Folder 2)
  - Boris Godunoff, 1962 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 2, Folder 5)
  - General Publicity, 1962 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 5, Folder 3, Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 6, Folder 9)
  - General Publicity, 1963 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 5, Folder 4)
  - Magic Flute, 1964 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 2, Folder 6)
  - Hartt Opera-25 Years, 1966 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 2, Folder 7)
  - La Boheme, 1966 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 5, Folder 5)
  - General Publicity, 1966 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 5, Folder 6)
  - General Publicity, 1967 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 5, Folder 7)
  - Macbeth, 1967 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 2, Folder 8)
  - General Publicity, 1968 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 2, Folder 9)
  - Charter Day-25 Years of Service, 1968 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 2, Folder 10)
  - "La vida breve", 1969 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 2, Folder 11)
  - "Nagy Sets Convey Hartt Opera Mood", 1969 Apr 21 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 6, Folder 10)
  - General Publicity, 1969 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 5, Folder 8)
  - Cosi Fan Tutti (Aspen Music Festival), 1970 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 6, Folder 11)
  - General Publicity, 1970 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 2, Folder 12, Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 6)
  - Pearl Fishers, 1971 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 2, Folder 14)
  - General Publicity, 1971 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 2, Folder 13)
  - University Library News, 2002 (Box Publicity and Scrapbooks 2, Folder 15)
- Opera Programs, Printed Ephemera, and Their Designs, 1942-1972; undated; VII
  This series consists of copies of opera programs directed by Elemer Nagy, as well as some printed ephemera for these productions. In some cases, the file includes original drawings and designs for these programs and printed materials (drawings and designs are located in oversize box).
  - Abduction from the Seraglio, 1968 (Box Programs 1, Folder 1)
  - Albert Herring, 1954; 1962 (Box Programs 1, Folder 2)
  - Amahl and the Night Visitors, 1954 (Box Programs 1, Folder 3)
  - Amelia Goes to the Ball, 1946 (Box Programs 1, Folder 4)
  - Ariadne of Naxos, 1967 (Box Programs 1, Folder 5, Box Programs 2, Folder 1)
  - Armide, 1957 Feb 9 (Box Programs 1, Folder 6)
  - Aspen Music Festival, 1961; 1969; undated (Box Programs 1, Folder 7)
  - Barber of Seville, 1947; 1963 (Box Programs 1, Folder 8)
  - Bastien and Bastienne, 1944-1945 (Box Programs 1, Folder 9)
  - The Beautiful Galatea, 1952 (Box Programs 1, Folder 10)
  - Beauty and the Beast, 1951; 1966-1967 (Box Programs 1, Folder 11)
  - Boris Godunoff, 1961-1962 (Box Programs 1, Folder 12)
  - The Cadi Outwitted, 1964 (Box Programs 1, Folder 13)
  - Central Opera Service Conference, 1957 (Box Programs 1, Folder 14)
  - Chatham College Opera Workshop, 1961 (Box Programs 1, Folder 15)
  - A Christmas Opera, 1952 Dec 16 (Box Programs 1, Folder 16)
  - Comedy on the Bridge, 1954 (Box Programs 1, Folder 17)
  - Cosi Fan Tutte, 1960; 1970 (Box Programs 1, Folder 18)
  - The Crucible, 1964 (Box Programs 1, Folder 19)
  - Cupid Goes To Boarding School, 1947 (Box Programs 1, Folder 20)
  - Deidama, 1958-1959 (Box Programs 1, Folder 21)
  - The Devil and Daniel Webster, 1953 (Box Programs 1, Folder 22)
  - Dialogues of the Carmelites, 1965 (Box Programs 1, Folder 23)
  - Don Giovanni, 1956 Feb (Box Programs 1, Folder 24)
  - Don Pasquale, 1950; 1961 (Box Programs 1, Folder 25)
  - Don Quixote, 1965 (Box Programs 1, Folder 26, Box Programs 2, Folder 2)
  - Duenna Prokofiev, 1970 (Box Programs 1, Folder 27)
  - Evening of Modern Opera, 1950 Jan 15 (Box Programs 1, Folder 28)
  - Falstaff, 1961 Feb (Box Programs 1, Folder 29)
  - Faust, 1955 (Box Programs 1, Folder 30)
  - Fidelio, 1963 Feb 21 (Box Programs 1, Folder 31)
  - Frantic Physician, 1970-1971 (Box Programs 1, Folder 32)
  - The Game of Cards, 1956 May (Box Programs 1, Folder 33)
  - Gianni Schicchi, 1947; undated (Box Programs 1, Folder 34)
  - The Golden Medal, 1954 Nov 20 (Box Programs 1, Folder 35)
  - The Goosehead and the Goblin, 1949 Dec 17; 1958 Mar 29 (Box Programs 1, Folder 36)
  - Hansel and Gretel, 1942-1958 (Box Programs 1, Folder 37)
  - Headless Horseman, 1951 Nov 17 (Box Programs 1, Folder 38)
  - HMS Pinafore, 1952 Apr (Box Programs 1, Folder 39)
  - La Boheme, 1966 (Box Programs 1, Folder 40)
  - The Love for Three Oranges, 1965-1966 (Box Programs 1, Folder 41)
  - Macbeth, 1953; 1967 (Box Programs 1, Folder 42)
  - Magic Flute, 1964 Feb (Box Programs 1, Folder 43, Box Programs 2, Folder 3)
  - Marriage by Lantern Light, 1943 (Box Programs 1, Folder 44)
  - Marriage of the Devil, 1945 Feb (Box Programs 1, Folder 45)
  - Marriage of Figaro, 1952; 1972 (Box Programs 1, Folder 46)
  - Martha, 1946; 1950 (Box Programs 1, Folder 47)
  - Medea, 1969-1970 (Box Programs 1, Folder 48)
  - Mefistofele, 1969 (Box Programs 1, Folder 49, Box Programs 2, Folder 4)
  - Mephistopheles, 1969 July (Box Programs 1, Folder 50)
  - Merry Wives of Windsor, 1951 (Box Programs 1, Folder 51)
  - Mighty Casey, 1953 May 4-6 (Box Programs 1, Folder 52)
  - Miranda and the Dark Young Man, 1956 May 9-12 (Box Programs 1, Folder 53)
  - Old Maid and the Thief, 1943; 1951; 1958 (Box Programs 1, Folder 54)
  - The Pearl Fishers, 1960 Feb; 1970-1971 (Box Programs 1, Folder 55, Box Programs 2, Folder 3, Folder 4)
  - Peer Gynt, 1966 Feb 23-26 (Box Programs 1, Folder 56, Box Programs 2, Folder 8)
  - Philemon and Baucis, 1957 May (Box Programs 1, Folder 57)
  - Polifem, 1949 May 11-14 (Box Programs 1, Folder 58)
  - Prelude and Fugue, 1958-1959 (Box Programs 1, Folder 59)
  - The Princess and the Maypole, 1952 Jul 6 (Box Programs 1, Folder 60)
  - The Princess and the Vagabond, 1948 May 13-15 (Box Programs 1, Folder 61)
  - Romeo and Juliet, 1948 Feb 18-21 (Box Programs 1, Folder 62)
  - Secret of Suzanne, 1945 Feb 27 (Box Programs 1, Folder 63)
  - Sister Angelica, 1945; 1947; 1971 (Box Programs 1, Folder 64)
  - Susannah, 1957-1958 (Box Programs 1, Folder 65)
  - Tales of Hoffman, 1968 (Box Programs 1, Folder 66, Box Programs 2, Folder 9)
  - Ten Maidens and No Man, 1942 May (Box Programs 1, Folder 67)
  - The Touchstone, 1955 May 4-7 (Box Programs 1, Folder 68)
  - The Turk in Italy, 1961 (Box Programs 1, Folder 69)
  - The Unicorn in the Garden, 1957 (Box Programs 1, Folder 70)
  - White Wings, 1949 Feb 9-12; 1950 (Box Programs 1, Folder 71)
  - The Young God-A Vaudeville, 1969 (Box Programs 1, Folder 72)
  - Millard Auditorium, undated (Box Programs 2, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified Operas, undated (Box Programs 1, Folder 73, Box Programs 2, Folder 10-11)
- Artifacts, 1962; undated; VIII
  The Artifacts series consists of two costumes designed by Elemer Nagy (for Bastien and Bastienne and Don Pasquale), as well as banners used by the Hartt Opera-Theater Guild on their European tour in 1962.
  - Bastien and Bastienne Costume, undated (Box Artifacts 1)
  - Don Pasquale Costume, undated (Box Artifacts 2)
  - European Tour Banners, 1962 (Box Artifacts 3)
- Duplicates, 1943-1970; undated; IX (Box Duplicates 1, Box Duplicates 2)
  This series consists of duplicate materials found in the collection and consists primarily of publicity materials and programs. Duplicate copies of other materials may exist elsewhere in the collection.